(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-26T05:59:37.892771",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
たった一つ たった一つの
Only one, only one...
たった一人 たった一人の
Only one, only one person...
私は ここは
I am here...
Here
[Song: Here]
枯れ木の胸 息もできない
With a withered heart, I can't even breathe,
降り出す雨 眠るように暗い
falling rain, dark as if asleep.
この世界を生き抜くのなら どんな花を飾ればいいの
If I am to survive in this world, what kind of flowers should I adorn?
信じたいくせに 信じられずに 無力で疎みな自分が
Even though I want to believe, I can't believe, a helpless and estranged self—
それでも心で抱くんだ こっちへおいでと 声が聞こえる
still, I hold it in my heart as a voice calls out "Come here."
無限で無謀な明日が それでもどこかで待つから たった一...
An infinite and reckless tomorrow still waits somewhere, just one...
目覚めた朝から
From the morning I woke up,
鳴り響く
it echoes,
夜明けの Blues
the dawn's blues.
孤独で儚い
Solitary and ephemeral,
夢を見る
I see a dream.
季節は巡り
Seasons turn,
Still I am standing
まだ I'm here
Still I'm here.
記憶と共に増えてく Scars
Scars increasing along with memories.
何度もブレることないこの炎は蒼く染まるよ
This unwavering flame is dyed in blue.
静かに熱く この胸を打つ
Quietly and passionately striking this heart,
いつまで経っても消える気がしない
feeling like it will never fade away.
溢れる想い中 恋焦がれているのは
Amidst overflowing feelings, what I yearn for
たった一つ One dream それだけを胸に
is just one, One dream, holding only that in my heart.
One day ただ見据えている One place
One day, just gazing ahead at One place.
あの頃には戻れないよ 今更
I can't go back to those days now.
Oh yeah yeah yeah oh yeah yeah
Just one This one
叶えていく One by one
Fulfilling them One by one.
築いていく Step by step
Building them Step by step.
未来を拓くこの一歩が全てを紡ぐ
This single step opening the future weaves everything.
あの日の涙も 輝かせる Diamond blue
Making even that day's tears shine, Diamond blue.
今解き放つ時が
The time to unleash it now.
溢れる想い中 譲れない気持ちなら
Amidst overflowing feelings, if it's an unwavering feeling,
たった一つ One dream それだけを胸に
just one, One dream, holding only that in my heart.
One day ただ見据えている One place
One day, just gazing ahead at One place.
あの頃には戻れないよ 今更
I can't go back to those days now.
Oh yeah yeah yeah oh yeah yeah
Just one This one
Don't give up your soul
絶えず戦いは続く だけどその先に見える景色は 全部お前のもの
The fight continues endlessly, but the scenery ahead is entirely yours.
描く理想も 手にするまでは Keep dreaming
Keep dreaming until you grasp the ideals you envision.
たった一つ One dream それだけを胸に
Just one, One dream, holding only that in my heart.
One day ただ見据えている One place
One day, just gazing ahead at One place.
あの頃には戻れないよ 今更
I can't go back to those days now.
Oh yeah yeah yeah oh yeah yeah
Just one This one
アローナ！ちゃんと見えてる？聞こえてる？
Alona! Can you see and hear me properly?
ということでホロライブ1期生の癒し系ハーフエルフ、アキ・ローゼンタールです！
I'm Aki Rosenthal, Hololive 1st Gen's healing half-elf!
今日は4周年記念ライブ「ROSE of the LAMP」をお届けしております！
Today I'm bringing you my 4th-anniversary live, "ROSE of the LAMP"!
歌ってだけのライブは初めてで緊張するけど、心を入れてアキローゼワールドを楽しんでもらえるように頑張ります！
It's my first singing-only live so I'm nervous, but I'll do my best so you can enjoy the AkiRose world!
一緒ににお祝いしてください！
Please celebrate with me!
たくさんのゲストも来るのでお楽しみに！
Lots of guests are coming too, so look forward to it!
それでは「ROSE of the LAMP」お楽しみください！
Now then, please enjoy "ROSE of the LAMP"!
幸せになれる隠しコマンドがあるらしい
There's supposedly a cheat code to become happy.
右、下、上、右、右、下、右
Right, down, up, right, right, down, right.
上、上、下、下、左、右、左、右
Up, up, down, down, left, right, left, right.
ちょっと、上にためてください。
Charge it a bit higher, please.
むしゃぶりじゃないか 不可能 可能
Isn't it munching? Impossible, possible!
とにもかくにもやってって 命令ばかり
Do whatever it takes, just orders!
なせばなるって精神ローン
Mental loan saying where there's a will there's a way.
マイナスばかりたまって馬鹿馬鹿バカ
Only negatives piling up, how foolish!
みんな！ここまでの隠しコマンドを正確にコンプリートするか、チャンネル登録をすると、私たちがもっとセクシーな姿に…！？
Everyone! If you complete the cheat codes so far or subscribe, we'll turn even sexier...!?
幸せに？
Become happy?
なりません。
That won't happen.
右 下 上 B A X Y L R 上 上 下 下 A Y L R A...
Right, down, up, A, B, X, Y, L, R, up, up, down, down, A, Y, L, R, A...
上 下 上 右 A Y L R A
...up, down, up, right, A, Y, L, R, A
右 下 上 右 A Y L R A
Right, down, up, right, A, Y, L, R, A
右 下 上 右 A Y L R A 上 上 下 下
Right, down, up, right, A, Y, L, R, A, up, up, down, down
左 回転 1回転 右 下 B A X Y L R
Left, spin, one spin, right, down, B, A, X, Y, L, R
上 上 下 下 A Y L R A
Up, up, down, down, A, Y, L, R, A
右 下 上 右 A Y L R A 上 上 下 下
Right, down, up, right, A, Y, L, R, A, up, up, down, down
ちょっと？
A bit?
間違えないでください！
Don't make any mistakes!
むちゃぶりじゃないか
Isn't this impossible?
学校 会社 頭ごなしの
School, company, head-shaking...
命令ばかり なせば成るって
...orders only, if you do it, it'll work out.
精神ローン マイナスばかり 回ってバカバカバカ
Mental roll, minus only, spin around!
チャンネル登録をすると
If you subscribe to the channel,
もっとセクシーな姿に！
you'll look even sexier!
なりません。
That won't happen.
まだまだ大丈夫 いけますよね？
It's still alright, we can go, right?
難易度高すぎるかもしれませんけどあなたなら出来るでしょう？
The difficulty might be too high, but for you, you can do it, right?
居残り 補習 出張 残業
Make-up exams, tutoring, business trips, overtime...
とにかくやってもらわないと
Anyway, if you don't do it...
とても困ります！
...we'll be in big trouble!
居残り 補習 出張 残業 課題 宿題
Tutoring, business trips, overtime, homework, tasks...
テスト 卒論 翻訳 任務 命令
...tests, thesis, translation, orders, missions...
責任 同期 期限 提出 明日
...responsibility, synchronization, deadlines, submissions, tomorrow...
部活 試合 練習 勝利 業者 相談 セット
...club match, practice, victory, businessman, consultation, set...
成立 進学 就職 転職 面接 回転 1回転
...formation, advancement, employment, retirement, interview, spin, one spin...
後輩 先輩 先生 上司 右 下 上 右
...upperclassman, senior, teacher, boss, right, down, up, right...
友人 同僚 彼氏 彼女 上 上 下 下
...friend, resignation, boyfriend, girlfriend, up, up, down, down...
左 右 Y L ヒーロー 心動 無用 セレクト スタート A B Y L R X
...left, right, Y, L, hero, heartbeat, word, use, select, start, A, B, Y, L, R, X...
右 左 上下 同時押し
...right, left, up, down, simultaneous press!
むちゃぶりじゃないか
Isn't this impossible?
不可能可能 とにかくやれて
If it's possible, anyway, just do it!
命令ばかり なせば成るって
Orders only, if you do it, it'll work out!
精神ローン マイナスばかり 貯まってバカバカバカ
Mental roll, minus only, saving up, ba-ba-ba-ba-ba!
むちゃぶりじゃないか
Isn't this impossible?
学校 会社 頭ごなしの 命令ばかり
School, company, head-shaking orders only...
なせば成るって 精神ローン マイナスばかり 貯まってバカバカバカ
...if you do it, it'll work out! Mental roll, minus only, saving up, ba-ba-ba-ba!
右 下 上 右 右 下 上 右 右 上 上 下 下
Right, down, up, right, right, down, up, right, right, up, up, down, down...
左 右 左 右 右 下 上 右 右 下 上 右 右
...left, right, left, right, right, down, up, right, right, down, up, right, right...
上 上 下 下 左 右 左 右 左 右 リセット
...up, up, down, down, left, right, left, right, left, right, reset.
哀れみをお下しなさい
Give me some mercy.
落ちた小鳥にそっと触れるような悲しみをお下しなさい
Give me such sadness like softly touching a fallen bird.
涙ぐんで 見下ろして 可哀想だと口に出して
Looking down with teary eyes, calling me pitiful,
靴の先端で転がしても構わないわ
it doesn't matter if I get turned over by the tip of a shoe.
汚れていてもいいからと 泥だらけの手を取って
It's fine even if I'm filthy, take my mud-stained hand,
ねぇ輪になって踊りましょう
hey, let's become a circle and dance!
目障りな有象無象は全て たべてしまいましょう
Let's eat up all the distracting tangible and intangible things,
スパイスは 耐え難いぐらいがいいわ
the spice should be just about unbearable.
lie, lie, lie, la la la...
怯えた小鳥は さよならなんて言えなくて
The frightened little bird could not say goodbye,
愛を請う仕草で黙り込んで
keeping silent with a pretense of begging for love,
つつましいつもりでいた
pretending to be modest all along.
lie, lie, it's a lie, not a lie, もう辛い
Lie, lie, it's a lie, not a lie, it's already painful.
散々傷ついて やさしいせかいに行きたいの
I want to go to a gentle world, having been hurt all over.
ひとつに溶かしてしまいましょう
Let's melt everything into one,
憎しみも 愛情もむしゃぶとほうばってしまいましょう
and recklessly embrace both hatred and affection.
混沌の甘い甘い壺の中で
Inside the sweet, sweet pot of chaos.
lie, lie, lie, la la la...
曖昧に笑うから 会いたいと思うのよ
I will laugh vaguely because I want to see you,
i know you're here to stay with me
愛されていたいだけ
I just want to be loved.
lie, lie, lie, you're to be with me
あわれみを下さい
Give me your pity
墜ちた小鳥にそっと触れるような
like when you gently hold a fallen little bird
かなしみを下さい
Give me your sadness
涙ぐんで見下ろして
be moved to tears, look down on me
可哀想だと口に出して
tell me how pitiful I am
擦り切れた傷跡さえも
Even these worn-out scars
消えてしまうの
will they just fade away?
やがてキラキラ夢の中
Before long, sparkling in a dream...
朽ちていく光は貴方に届くはずだから
The light fading away should reach you
まぶしくて涙が止まらない
Dazzling, my tears won't stop
ねえどうかすっと側にいて
Hey, please stay right by my side
泥だらけの手を取って離さないで
Take my muddied hand and don't let go
どうかずっと側にいて離さないで
Please stay by my side forever, don't let go
暗くなる側いて離さないで
Staying by my side as it grows dark, don't let go
見えないわただずっと側にいて
I can't see, just stay by my side forever
離さないでただずっと側いて
Don't let go, just stay by my side forever
眩しくて涙が止まらない
Dazzling, my tears won't stop
目と目がそばにいて
Eyes close together, stay by my side
泥だらけの手を取って離さないで
Take my muddied hand and don't let go
どうかずっと側にいて離さないで
Please stay by my side forever, don't let go
暗くなるのそばにいて離さないで見えないわ
Getting dark, stay by my side, don't let go, I can't see
ただずっと側にいて離さないでただずっと愛してる
Just stay by my side forever, don't let go, I've always loved you
この世で造花より綺麗な花はないわ
In this world, there are no flowers prettier than artificial ones
何故ならば全ては嘘で作れている
Because they're all made of lies
antipathy world,
絶望の雨はあたしの傘を突いて
The rain of despair pierces my umbrella
湿らす前髪とこころの裏面
Dampening my bangs and the back of my heart
煩わしいわ
It's so annoying
何時しかことの葉は疾うに枯れきっていて
Before I knew it, the leaves of words had withered away
事の実があたしに熟れている
And the fruits of reality are ripening on me
鏡に映り嘘を描いて
Reflecting in the mirror, drawing lies
自らを見失った絵画
A painting that lost itself
パッパパラパッパパラパッパパラ
Pappa-para-pappara-ra-pappa
謎々数えて遊びましょう
Let's count riddles and play a game
タッタタラタッタラタッタラ
Tatta-tara-tattara-ra-tatta
何故何故此処で踊っているのでしょう
Why, oh why are we dancing here?
簡単なことも分からないわ
I don't even understand simple things
あたしって何だっけ
What am I, again?
それすら夜の手に拘束されて
Even that is bound by the hands of night
愛のように消える
Fading away like love
さよならも言えず呻いていた
Groaning, unable to even say goodbye
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ
Phony, phony, phony
嘘に絡まっているあたしは
Entangled in lies, I am...
antipathy world,
何時しか切なるなの願いが何になって
Before I knew it, what did my earnest wishes become?
異色の眼鏡だわ遠いてる
Colored glasses, far away
鏡に映るあたしを描いて
Drawing myself reflected in the mirror
誰しもが見間違ったフェイク
A fake that everyone mistook
どうして愛なんてものに群がり
Why do people flock to things like love
それを欲して生きるのだ
And live desiring it?
今日も泳いでる夜の電車が通り過ぎていく
Today too, the night train swims past
踊り明かせよ
Let's dance the night away
何故何故此処で痛むのでしょう
Why, oh why does it hurt here?
散々なお前は変わらないわ
You, having been through so much, never change
絶望の雨は止まないわ
The rain of despair won't stop
さよならも言えず呻いていた
Groaning, unable to even say goodbye
嘘に絡まっている
Entangled in lies
ただ
Just...
簡単なことも分からないわ
I don't even understand simple things
あたしって何だっけ
What am I, again?
それすら夜の手に拘束されて
Even that is bound by the hands of night
愛のように消える
Fading away like love
さよならまたねと呟いた
Muttering goodbye, see you later
嘘に絡まっているあたしは
Entangled in lies, I am...
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ 嘘に絡まっている
Phony, phony, phony, entangled in lies
造花だけが知っている秘密のフォニイ
The secret phony known only by artificial flowers
この世で造花より綺麗な花はないわ
There are no flowers more beautiful than artificial ones in this world
何故ならば総ては嘘で出来ている antipathy world
Because everything is made of lies, antipathy world
絶望の雨はあしたの傘を突いて
The rain of despair pierces tomorrow's umbrella
湿らす前髪とこころの背面
Dampening my bangs and the back of my heart
煩わしいわ
It's so annoying
何時しか言葉の葉は疾むに枯れきって
Before I knew it, the leaves of words withered away in sickness
事の実はあしたに熟れている
And the truth of the matter ripens into tomorrow
鏡に映り嘘を描いて
Reflected in the mirror, drawing a lie,
自らを見失った絵画
A painting where I lost sight of myself
パパッパラパッパララッパッパ
Pa pappara pappara rap pappa
謎々かざして遊びましょう
Let's play holding up riddles
タタッラタッララッラッラ
Tat attarat att ararat tatta
何故何故此処で踊っているのでしょう
Why, oh why, are we dancing here?
色彩のブルース
[Colorful Blues]
昨日の夢 オレンジ色の羽り
My dream last night, orange wings
今日の夢 沈黙の気配示す
My dream tonight, showing a hint of silence
アルコールの川をゆっくり渡る
I leisurely cross a river of alcohol
長ぐつのリズム 心で酔いましょう
Let's get intoxicated in our hearts to the rhythm of boots
鉛の指から流れるメロディー
A melody streaming from leaden fingers
激しく染める光の渦
A whirlpool of light dyeing us fiercely
あかりの色が奏でるブルース
Blues played by the color of the lights
やさしく泣いている吐息に甘ませて…
Let me indulge in your tender, sobbing sighs...
目に浮かぶ裏通りの風景画
A landscape painting of side streets in my mind
ひしめき合うざれ合った声の洪水
A flood of crowded, mingling voices
モノクロームの中に閉じ込めた姿を
The figure contained within monochrome
遠い約束リズムでかわしましょう
Let's make distant promises with our rhythm
吐き出す言葉に熱いメロディー
The passionate melody to the words I spit out
切なくよみがえるデジャブの香り
A bittersweet, reviving scent of deja vu
心を溶かす色彩のブルース
Colorful blues that melt my heart
甘くささやいた吐息が眠るまで…
Until your sweet, whispering sighs fall asleep...
昨日の夢 オレンジ色の羽り
My dream last night, orange wings
今日の夢 沈黙の気配示す
My dream tonight, showing a hint of silence
アルコールの川をゆっくり渡る
I leisurely cross a river of alcohol
長ぐつのリズム 心で酔いましょう
Let's get intoxicated in our hearts to the rhythm of boots
鉛の指から流れるメロディー
A melody streaming from leaden fingers
激しく染める光の渦
A whirlpool of light dyeing us fiercely
あかりの色が奏でるブルース
Blues played by the color of the lights
やさしく泣いている吐息に甘ませて…
Let me indulge in your tender, sobbing sighs...
目に浮かぶ裏通りの風景画
A landscape painting of side streets in my mind
ひしめき合うざれ合った声の洪水
A flood of crowded, mingling voices
モノクロームの中に閉じ込めた姿を
The figure contained within monochrome
遠い約束リズムでかわしましょう
Let's make distant promises with our rhythm
吐き出す言葉に熱いメロディー
The passionate melody to the words I spit out
切なくよみがえるデジャブの香り
A bittersweet, reviving scent of deja vu
心を溶かす色彩のブルース
Colorful blues that melt my heart
甘くささやいた吐息が眠るまで…
Until your sweet, whispering sighs fall asleep...
昨日の夢 オレンジ色の羽り
My dream last night, orange wings
今日の夢 沈黙の気配示す
My dream tonight, showing a hint of silence
アルコールの川をゆっくり渡る
I leisurely cross a river of alcohol
長ぐつのリズム 心で酔いましょう
Let's get intoxicated in our hearts to the rhythm of boots
鉛の指から流れるメロディー
A melody streaming from leaden fingers
激しく染める光の渦
A whirlpool of light dyeing us fiercely
あかりの色が奏でるブルース
Blues played by the color of the lights
やさしく泣いている吐息に甘ませて…
Let me indulge in your tender, sobbing sighs...
目に浮かぶ裏通りの風景画
A landscape painting of side streets in my mind
ひしめき合うざれ合った声の洪水
A flood of crowded, mingling voices
モノクロームの中に閉じ込めた姿を
The figure contained within monochrome
遠い約束リズムでかわしましょう
Let's make distant promises with our rhythm
吐き出す言葉に熱いメロディー
The passionate melody to the words I spit out
切なくよみがえるデジャブの香り
A bittersweet, reviving scent of deja vu
心を溶かす色彩のブルース
Colorful blues that melt my heart
甘くささやいた吐息が眠るまで…
Until your sweet, whispering sighs fall asleep...
鉛の指から流れるメロディー
A melody streaming from leaden fingers
激しく染める光の渦
A whirlpool of light dyeing us fiercely
あかりの色が奏でるブルース
Blues played by the color of the lights
やさしく泣いている吐息に甘ませて…
Let me indulge in your tender, sobbing sighs...
ささやいていた息吹が
A whispering breath...
眠るまで
Until I fall asleep...
ストレート ドキドキする
Straight, my heart is pounding,
視線はまるで レーザービーム
Your gaze is like a laser beam.
心をシュワッと突き刺すの
It pierces right through my heart,
虹色のラブビーム
A rainbow-colored love beam.
実る果実が水を弾いて
Like droplets bouncing off ripe fruit,
キラキラしてる光に似てる
It resembles sparkling light.
グランドに立つキミの姿が
The sight of you standing on the ground
まぶしくて少し照れちゃうけど
Is so dazzling it makes me a bit shy.
レーザービーム
[Song: Laser Beam]
ストレート まっすぐだね
Straight, so direct,
恋愛はきっと レーザービーム
Romance is surely a laser beam.
心をシュワッと突き刺すの
It pierces right through my heart,
虹色のラブビーム
A rainbow-colored love beam.
ふたりを繋ぐ秘密の光
The secret light connecting us two,
あの日見つけた秘密の光
The secret light we found that day.
恋の瞬間 音は止まって
The moment we fell in love, time stood still,
時間はスローリーに恋の光線
And time slowly turns into a love ray.
ストレート ドキドキする
Straight, my heart is pounding,
視線はまるで レーザービーム
Your gaze is like a laser beam.
心をシュワッと突き刺すの
It pierces right through my heart,
虹色のラブビーム
A rainbow-colored love beam.
ストレート まっすぐだね
Straight, so direct,
恋愛はきっと レーザービーム
Romance is surely a laser beam.
心をシュワッと突き刺すの
It pierces right through my heart,
虹色のラブビーム
A rainbow-colored love beam.
ふたりを繋ぐ秘密の光
The secret light connecting us two,
あの日見つけた秘密の光
The secret light we found that day.
恋の瞬間 音は止まって
The moment we fell in love, time stood still,
時間はスローリーに恋の光線
And time slowly turns into a love ray.
ストレート ドキドキする
Straight, my heart is pounding,
視線はまるで レーザービーム
Your gaze is like a laser beam.
心をシュワッと突き刺すの
It pierces right through my heart,
虹色のラブビーム
A rainbow-colored love beam.
ふたりを繋ぐ秘密の光
The secret light connecting us two,
あの日見つけた秘密の光
The secret light we found that day.
恋の瞬間 音は止まって
The moment we fell in love, time stood still,
時間はスローリーに恋の光線
And time slowly turns into a love ray.
ストレート まっすぐだね
Straight, so direct,
恋愛はきっと レーザービーム
Romance is surely a laser beam.
心をシュワッと突き刺すの
It pierces right through my heart,
虹色のラブビーム
A rainbow-colored love beam.
恋の瞬間 音は止まって
The moment we fell in love, time stood still,
時間はスローリーに恋の光線
And time slowly turns into a love ray.
ストレート ドキドキする
Straight, my heart is pounding,
視線はまるで レーザービーム
Your gaze is like a laser beam.
心をシュワッと突き刺すの
It pierces right through my heart,
虹色のラブビーム
A rainbow-colored love beam.
ふたりを繋ぐ秘密の光
The secret light connecting us two,
あの日見つけた秘密の光
The secret light we found that day.
恋の瞬間 音は止まって
The moment we fell in love, time stood still,
時間はスローリーに恋の光線
And time slowly turns into a love ray.
ストレート まっすぐだね
Straight, so direct,
恋愛はきっと レーザービーム
Romance is surely a laser beam.
心をシュワッと突き刺すの
It pierces right through my heart,
虹色のラブビーム
A rainbow-colored love beam.
ふたりを繋ぐ秘密の光
The secret light connecting us two,
あの日見つけた秘密の光
The secret light we found that day.
恋の瞬間 音は止まって
The moment we fell in love, time stood still,
時間はスローリーに恋の光線
And time slowly turns into a love ray.
ストレート ドキドキする
Straight, my heart is pounding,
視線はまるで レーザービーム
Your gaze is like a laser beam.
心をシュワッと突き刺すの
It pierces right through my heart,
虹色のラブビーム
A rainbow-colored love beam.
ストレート まっすぐだね
Straight, so direct,
恋愛はきっと レーザービーム
Romance is surely a laser beam.
おっとっと
Oops-a-daisy,
黒い夜はバラ色じゃない
The dark night isn't rose-colored,
夢のせいで踊りましょう
Let's dance because of the dream.
ROSE of the LAMP
[Song: ROSE of the LAMP]
黒い夜はバラ色じゃない
The dark night isn't rose-colored,
夢のせいで踊りましょう
Let's dance because of the dream.
夜明けまで踊り明かそう
Let's dance the night away until dawn.
私と take a step yeah
With you, take a step, yeah
今宵はバラ色 night
Tonight is a rose-colored night
夢をのせて 踊りましょう
Carrying dreams, let's dance
（アローナ！）
(Arona!)
なんたって
After all,
触れたい 知りたい 隠した想い
I want to touch, know, and hide my feelings
月が綺麗ね、ロマンティック
The moon is lovely, how romantic
時には甘く 熟れた果実のように
Sometimes sweet, like a ripened fruit,
キミにそっと 囁くの
whispering softly to you.
情熱の誘うままに ねぇ
Following where passion leads, hey...
本当の素顔見せて
Show me your true face,
もっと
even more!
give me gimme love！
Give me, gimme love!
私の全てを
All of me,
だって
because...
crazy in crazy in love
本気魅せてあげる
I'll show you my true seriousness!
アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra,
abracadabra,
キミと出逢えた奇跡に
to the miracle of meeting you,
アブラカタブラ
abracadabra,
愛を込めて 踊りましょう
let's dance with love poured in!
（アローナ！）
(Arona!)
いつだって 笑って 悩んで 迷える日々も
Always smiling, worrying, and wandering days,
なんて素敵な ドラマティック
how wonderful, how dramatic.
そうやって 探って 感じて 重ね合わせて
Searching, feeling, overlapping like that,
キミにちょっと 近づくの
getting a little closer to you.
鼓動が叫ぶ くらいほら
To the point my heartbeat cries out,
本能で強く 惹かれそうよ
instinctively drawn so strongly to you.
give me gimme love！
Give me, gimme love!
溶かししてあげるわ
I'll melt you away,
きっと
surely,
fall in fall in love
need you 止められないの
need you, I can't stop it.
アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra,
abracadabra,
こんな素晴らしい世界に
to such a wonderful world,
アブラカタブラ
abracadabra,
キミのために 踊りましょう
let's dance for your sake!
（アローナ！）
(Arona!)
もう ギリギリで ギリギリが 私のココロ
Already on the edge, my heart is at its limit,
baby キミだけに キミだけに 全部 届けたいよ
baby, only to you, I want to deliver it all.
give me gimme love！
Give me, gimme love!
私の全てを
All of me,
crazy in crazy in love
本気魅せてあげる
I'll show you my true seriousness!
アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra,
abracadabra,
キミと出逢えた奇跡に
to the miracle of meeting you,
アブラカタブラ
abracadabra,
愛を込めて 踊りましょう
let's dance with love poured in!
（アローナ！）
(Arona!)
はい！
Hi!
続いてはこの曲だー！
Up next is this song!
夢見る あなたの 力になりたい
I want to become your strength as you dream.
涙は頬を伝 瞳は赤く燃える
Tears stream down cheeks, eyes burn red.
稲妻のように激しく 誰かが愛を叫ぶ
Violently like lightning, someone cries out for love.
例えどんな闇でも一人じゃないよね？
Even in any darkness, you're not alone, right?
私たちを照らす moonlight
The moonlight that illuminates us.
嗟嘆 女子にも譲れない矜持がある
Ah, even girls have an unyielding pride.
それは王子様に運命託さず 自らたたかう意志
The will to fight oneself, not entrusting fate to a prince.
shiny make-up 輝くよ 星空を集めて
Shiny make-up, shining, gathering the starry sky.
女の子にも譲れぬ今日日がある
Even girls have things they won't give up today—
それはおじさまに運命投げず
not leaving fate to middle-aged men,
自ら戦う意志
fighting with their own will.
Shiny Make-up！ 輝くよ 星空を集めて
Shiny Make-up! Shining bright, gathering the starry sky,
ただ守られるだけの かよわい存在じゃないわ
I'm not just a fragile being meant only to be protected.
悲しみの波に揺られ
Rocked by the waves of sadness,
怒りの火に焼かれても
Even if burned by the fires of anger,
稲妻のように眩く
Dazzling like lightning,
永遠の愛を誓う
Swearing eternal love.
たとえ今は離れていても
Even if we are apart right now,
一人じゃないよね？
I'm not alone, right?
私たちを繋ぐ moonlight
The moonlight connects us.
Ah 女の子には無敵の武器がある
Ah, girls have a weapon of invincibility,
それは弱さに寄り添うまなざしと 全て受け入れる強さ
A gaze that embraces weakness and the strength to accept everything.
Shiny Make-up！ きらめくよ 星空に抱かれて
Shiny Make-up! Glittering, embraced by the starry sky,
時を超えた絆が 私に勇気をくれる
A bond transcending time gives me courage.
恋しくて 切なくて 泣きたくなるよ
Yearning, painful, making me want to cry.
会いたくて 寂しくて 駆け出しそうなハート
Wanting to see you, lonely, a heart ready to dash out.
この広い宇宙で 何度生まれ変わっても あなたに恋をする
In this vast universe, no matter how many times I'm reborn, I'll fall in love with you.
Shiny Make-up！ 羽ばたくよ 星空の彼方へ
Shiny Make-up! Soaring to the far side of the starry sky,
罪が回る世界でも 未来を信じられる だから
Even in a world where sin turns, I can believe in the future, so—
Shiny Make-up！ 戦うよ 星空を纏って
Shiny Make-up! Fighting, draped in the starry sky,
新しい伝説が 今ここから始まる
A new legend begins right here and now.
La la Pretty Guardian Sailor Moon
せーの！ ４周年おめでとう！
Ready, set! Happy 4th anniversary!
ありがとう～！
Thank you so much!
じゃあせっかくだし、４周年のお祝いなんだから他の同期生も呼んじゃおうか！
Since it's the 4th anniversary, let's invite the other classmates too!
いいねー！
Sounds great!
じゃあ、頑張ってねー！
Then do your best!
バイバーイ！ ありがとう！
Bye-bye! Thank you!
よし、じゃあメルちゃん行きますか！
Alright, shall we go, Mel-chan?
うん！
Yeah!
ミュージック、スタート！
Music, start!
輝く夜空 四季巡って
Shining night sky, the four seasons revolve,
春風 君を乗せて 夏色が迎えるよ
Spring breeze carrying you, summer colors greet us.
色めく秋が 背中を押したら
When colorful autumn pushes our backs,
もふもふ吹雪 キラメキ
Fluffy blizzard, sparkling.
めぐりめぐハート
Hearts turning and turning.
何にもわからない 一歩進んで
Taking a step forward knowing nothing,
やっとここまで辿り着けたね
We finally made it this far.
待ち遠しいね (ずっーと！)
We've been looking forward to it (always!)
素敵なステージ
A wonderful stage
一番に絶対見せてあげるよ！ (おー！)
We'll definitely show you the best one! (Oh!)
行こうぜ smile ! smile ! catch up , future !
Let's go, smile! smile! catch up, future!
無敵に奔る季節が 世界を駆け巡って夢のような日々へと
The invincible running seasons race around the world toward dreamlike days.
光れ bright ! bright ! light up , future !
Shine bright! bright! light up, future!
僕らが一番星！
We are the number one star!
そうさ！ 照らし続けようぜ
That's right! Let's keep shining.
スポットライトはついたばかり
The spotlight has only just turned on.
赤らむ頬のイルミネーション
Illumination of flushed cheeks,
ココロは色とりどり 弾き舞うフェスティバル
Hearts multicolored, dancing in a festival.
幸せいっぱい注ぐロゼグラス
A rosé glass filled with happiness.
輝く夜空 四季巡って
Radiant night sky, as the four seasons turn,
春風君を乗せて 夏色が迎えるよ
the spring breeze carries you as summer welcomes us.
色めく秋が背中を押したら
And if colorful autumn gives you a push from behind,
もふもふ吹雪 キラメキタ
a fluffy blizzard sparkles brightly!
巡り巡るハート
Hearts spinning and turning around...
なににもわからない 一歩進んで
Not knowing anything, taking a step forward,
やっとここまで辿り着けたね
we finally made it all the way here!
待ちわびてる (ずーっと！)
We've been waiting so long! (Always!)
素敵なステージ 一番に絶対見せてあげるよ！ (おー！)
We'll show you the most wonderful stage first! (Oh!)
行こうよ smile! smile! catch up, future!
Let's go, smile! smile! Catch up, future!
無敵に昂る季節が 世界を駆け巡って 夢のような日々へと
An invincibly high-spirited season races around the world, toward dreamlike days.
光れ bright! bright! light up, future!
Shine bright! bright! Light up, future!
僕らが一等星！ そうさ！ 照らし続けよう
We are first-class stars! That's right! Let's keep on shining.
スポットライトはついたばかり
The spotlight has just turned on,
赤らむ頬のイルミネーション
illuminating our blushing cheeks.
ココロは色とりどり 弾き舞うフェスティバル
Our hearts are a colorful, dancing festival!
幸せいっぱいいっぱい 灌ぐローズグラス
Pouring full of happiness into a rose glass.
鳴らしてキラッと染めるよ
Let's ring it and dye it with a sparkle!
真っ白な気持ち
With pure white feelings,
12時の鐘なんか忘れちゃって
let's forget about the 12 o'clock bell...
ずっと解けない魔法を掛けよう
and cast a spell that never wears off!
ときめかせて (そっと)
Make it flutter (softly),
胸高鳴る時間を贈るから 絶対ついておいでよ！ (おー！)
giving you a heart-throbbing time, so be sure to follow us! (Oh!)
届け spark! spark! pop-up, future!
Reach spark! spark! Pop-up, future!
いまを駆ける五つ星 世界も巻き込んで賑やかに遊ぼう
Five stars running through the present, pulling the world into our lively play!
ずっと flash! flash! make up, future!
Always flash! flash! Make up, future!
目も眩むシチュエーション まだ踊り足りないでしょ？
A dazzling situation—you haven't danced enough yet, right?
カーテンコールのずっとずっと先まで
Far, far beyond the curtain call,
楽しむ気持ちさえ持ってきたなら
if you've brought along the desire to have fun,
きっと誰もが主人公になれるよ
anyone can surely become the protagonist!
羽も尻尾も笑顔もさらけ出して
Bare your wings, tail, and smiles,
もっと step! (step!) もっと jump! (jump!)
and step! (step!) More jump! (jump!)
またとないこの世界を 一緒に遊び尽くそう！ (おー！)
Let's play this one-of-a-kind world to the fullest together! (Oh!)
響き clap! clap! let’s sing, future!
Resound clap! clap! Let's sing, future!
このメロディが終わっても 決して今日だけの思い出にはしないよ
Even if this melody ends, we will never let it be just today's memory.
と言うことで、1期生オリジナル曲「Plasmagic Seasons!」をお届けしましたー！
And with that, we performed our 1st gen original song "Plasmagic Seasons!"!
はい、魔法の天才・ヴァンパイアよぞらメルです！
Yes, I'm Yozora Mel, the vampire of magical genius!
アキちゃん今日は誘ってくれてありがとう！またね、1期生のみんなでこの曲が歌えてメルはとっても嬉しかったです。
Aki-chan, thanks for inviting me today! I'm so happy we all got to sing this song together as 1st gen.
そしてメルも5月13日に活動4周年を迎えました！まだ3D配信はできていないんですが、予定はあるのでみんなお楽しみに！
And Mel also celebrated her 4th anniversary on May 13th! I haven't done my 3D stream yet, but I have plans so look forward to it!
はい、次ハートちゃん！はい、6月2日21時から記念配信するから見に来てね！そして今日はアキちゃんおめでとう！
Yes, next is Haato-chan! Yes, I'm having my anniversary stream on June 2nd at 9 PM, so come watch! And congratulations today, Aki-chan!
ありがとう！次ふぶきちゃん！
Thank you! Next is Fubuki-chan!
はい、6月3日からなと、白上も記念配信があります！よろしくお願いしますよーい！
Yes, starting June 3rd, Nato, Shirakami will also have an anniversary stream! Please look forward to it!
ありがとう！そしてまつりちゃん！
Thank you! And Matsuri-chan!
はい、えーっと、6月4日に記念配信を予定しております！よろしくお願いします！
Yes, um, I'm planning my anniversary stream on June 4th! Please look forward to it!
はい、ありがとう！はい、ということでいっぱい盛り上げてくれると嬉しいです。みんなありがとねー！
Yes, thank you! So we'd be happy if you get super hyped. Thank you everyone!
バイバイ！じゃあ次は無口で3Dなんだな(笑) 無口でね、だね！あ、まつりちゃんはお残し、お残しだよ。
Bye-bye! Next is Mukuchi in 3D (laughs) Mukuchi, right! Ah, Matsuri-chan is leaving leftovers, leftovers!
サマローズで歌おうと思って、お！サマローズオッケー！最後までいきましょう！ドキドキするけど楽しみ！
Thinking of singing it at Summer Rose, oh! Summer Rose okay! Let's go till the end! I'm nervous but looking forward to it!
「またね」と笑って見せてくれた
You smiled and told me, "See you later,"
同じように笑い返していたのに気づけば
and I smiled right back just like you, but before I knew it,
少し滲んでいた あなたの姿
your figure was slightly blurred with tears.
あれからいくつ夜を越えた
How many nights have passed since then?
窓越しの白い画面に映ったあなたと見たい景色を今もずっとずっと見つめたまま
I'm still gazing at the scenery I wanted to see with you, reflected on the white screen across the window...
きょうも 今も ずっと ずっと 見つめたまま
Today and right now, gazing at you forever and ever...
降りしきる雪が積もるように
Like snow falling and piling up,
この街で ただあなたを思う
In this town, I simply think of you.
離れていても 同じ空が どうか 見えてますように
Even apart, I hope the same sky is visible to you...
胸を打つ やさしい声が響く
A gentle voice that strikes my heart echoes,
耳元に あなたが残したしじま
In my ear, the silence you left behind...
世界が 切り離された夜 また目を潤す
On a night when the world was cut off, my eyes grow moist once more.
くだらないことにずっと 幸せを感じてた きっと
We always felt happy over trivial things, surely.
特別じゃない日々を もっと 二人でただ過ごしたくて
Wanting to spend more ordinary days together just the two of us,
季節が何度変わろうと 隣にいたよね それ以上何もいらないから
No matter how many seasons change, you were right beside me—I needed nothing more than that.
降りしきる雪が積もるように
Like snow falling and piling up,
遠い街で ただあなたを思う
In a distant town, I simply think of you.
触れ合うことができなくても 変わることなく
Even if we cannot touch, unchangingly,
何度だってそう 振り返れば あの日のあなたの
No matter how many times, yes, if I look back, your words and voice from that day...
言葉が 声が 会いたくなるんだよ
Make me want to see you so badly.
何度だってそう 信じ合えれば いつまでも二人 繋がっていられる
No matter how many times, if we believe in each other, we can stay connected forever.
雪あかり照らす この街にも
Even upon this town illuminated by snowlight,
いつかは優しい 春が訪れる
A gentle spring will one day arrive.
ここでまた会えたその時は 涙零さないように
When we meet again here, so I won't spill tears,
冬の終わりを告げる 歌よ
O song that announces the end of winter,
その一瞬に願いを乗せる どんな季節も景色も あなたと共に
I place my wish in that single moment—every season and scenery, together with you.
同じ場所で感じていたい
I want to feel them in the same place.
街に柔らかい風が吹いて 鮮やかな花が咲くその日を
As a soft wind blows through the town, the day when vibrant flowers bloom,
待ち続ける二人にも ああ 春が訪れるように
I pray spring will visit the two of us who keep waiting...
笑顔で また会えますように
So we may meet again with a smile.
歌よ 作詞:中村佳穂 作曲:Ludvig Forssell
[Song: Uta yo | Lyrics: Kaho Nakamura | Music: Ludvig Forssell]
歌よ 導いて
O song, guide me.
こんな小さなメロディが
Such a tiny melody
貫いてく 世界が見たいの
piercing through—I want to see that world.
毎朝起きて 探してる
Every morning I wake up and search
あなたのいない未来は 想像したくない
I don't want to imagine a future without you.
いやなの
I hate it.
でももういない 世界がわかんない
You're gone, and I don't understand this world.
私以外 うまくいってるみたい
It seems everyone else is doing fine.
それでもあしたは来る
Still, tomorrow will come.
どれだけの…
Just how much...
歌よ 導いて！
O song, guide me!
闇になる みな幸せなの
Turning into darkness—is everyone happy?
愛している 人がいるの
Is there someone you love?
こうして 一人でいると
When I'm all alone like this,
不安になる 歌よ
I grow afraid, O song.
導いて どんなことが起きてもいい
Guide me, no matter what happens.
歌よ
O song,
そばにいて
stay by my side.
愛よ 近づいて
O love, draw near.
きらめきの花 夢の宝石 世界は美しい
Sparkling flowers, jewels of dreams—the world is beautiful.
怯えと不安 縛られるけれど
Though bound by fear and anxiety,
強く優しく なれたなら
if I could become strong and kind...
あの空は 戻らない
That sky will never return.
ひとりでは 生きてられない
I cannot live all by myself.
会いたい もう一度
I want to see you once more;
胸の奥ふるえている
deep within my chest, I'm trembling.
ここにいるよ とどいて
I'm right here, please reach out—
はなれてはならない 君へ
to you, from whom I must never part.
目を閉じた時にだけ 会えるなんて 信じない
I won't believe I can only meet you when I close my eyes.
はなれてはならない 君へ
To you, from whom I must never part...
会いたい
I want to see you—
はなれてはならない 君へ
to you, from whom I must never part.
きらめきの花 夢の宝石
Sparkling flowers, jewels of dreams,
世界は美しい
the world is beautiful.
ひとりでは 生きてられない
I cannot live all by myself.
会いたい もう一度
I want to see you once more.
ここにいるよ とどいて
I'm right here, please reach out—
はなれてはならない 君へ
to you, from whom I must never part.
一人にして欲しいと
"I just want you to be alone," you say,
あなたは突き放すけれど
pushing me away, but
本当は胸の中にあるものを 覗かれたくないのでしょう？
surely you don't want me to see what's truly inside your heart, right?
夜が
Night
また訪れるのだけどね
falls upon us once again, but...
あなた あなたは どんなあなたでも
No matter what kind of person you are,
見たいと いつも考えてしまう
I always find myself wanting to see you.
聞かせて
Let me hear
隠そうとする あなたの顔を
the face you try to hide,
見せて 隠れてしまう あなたの心
let me see the heart you keep hidden away.
聞かせて どんなことからでもいい 最後まで聞くから
Let me hear it, no matter what it is, I'll listen to the very end.
開いて 傍に行きたい あなたの心
Open up, I want to be by your side, your heart.
ララ、ララ、ララ、ララ…
La-la, la-la, la-la, la-la...
あなたの 心
Your heart...
聞かせて
Let me hear it...
そっと開いたドアの向こうに
Beyond the door you opened softly
壊れそうな世界はある
Lies a world that seems to be destroyed
朝が来るのか 夜になるのか
Will the morning come? Will it become night?
迷いながら ひかりは澱んで
As you lose your way the light breaks through
声が呼ぶまでは もう少し遊ぼう
Let's play a little longer until the voice calls for me,
花のように廻る時間を繰り返し
Repeating the time that revolves like a flower
夢はこの部屋の中で 優しい歌をずっと君に歌っていた
Dreams were always singing a gentle song to you here in this room
何がほんとのことなの
What is the truth?
一番強く信じられる世界を 追いかけて 君の銀の庭へ
Chase after the world that you can believe in the most to your silver garden
道に迷ったあの子が今日も 一番早く帰り着いた
The girl who lost her way today too came home the earliest
正しさよりも明るい場所を 見つけながら走ればいいんだね
She should run while finding a place brighter than righteousness, right?
幼い眠りを守りたい番人
The guard who wants to protect your childish slumber
大人になる門は固く閉ざされて
Keeps the gate to becoming an adult tightly closed
君は気付いていたかな
Had you noticed?
本当のことなんて いつも過去にしかない
That the truth is always left in the past?
未来や希望は 全て 誰かが描く遠い庭の我が儘な物語
Future and hope are all selfish tales of a faraway garden drawn by someone else
まだ誰も知らない ひたむきな小鳥の声で歌う子供は
The children singing with the voice of an earnest little bird that no one knows yet
何を隠し 何を壊し 燃える時計
What are they hiding, what are they destroying, a burning clock
秘密めく花の香り
The secret scent of flowers
ここにいるよ
"I am right here."
静かに寄り添って 何処にも行かないで
Nestling close quietly, please don't go anywhere
窓辺で囁いて 何処にも行かないで
Whispering by the window, please don't go anywhere
夢はその腕の中に
Dreams lie in those arms
優しい人の嘘も 嘆きも閉じ込めていたか
Locking away the lies and grievances of kind people
何か足りない心で
With a heart that is lacking something
光を纏い飛んで行こう 少女のかたちをして
Let us bask in the light and take off, taking the form of a little girl
終わらない始まりへ 本当の終わりへ
Towards the never-ending beginning, towards the true ending
静かに寄り添って 何処にも行かないで
Nestling close quietly, please don't go anywhere
窓辺で囁いて 何処にも行かないで
Whispering by the window, please don't go anywhere
本日はアキロゼ4周年ライブ「ROSE of the LAMP」1週間でしたかー？
How was the first week of Aki Rosenthal's 4th Anniversary Live, "ROSE of the LAMP"?
はい！それではかっこいいオープニングから始まり、たくさんたくさん楽しませていただきました！5年目も活動頑張っていきたいと思うので応援よろしくお願いします！
Yes! Starting with a really cool opening, I had so much fun! I want to keep working hard in my 5th year, so I'd appreciate your support!
さあ、ここで超ハッピーなお知らせ！
Now, here is a super happy announcement!
4周年を記念してスペシャルなグッズを作らせていただきました！
We've made some special goods to commemorate the 4th anniversary!
今回のライブ＆新曲「ROSE of the LAMP」のロゴをモチーフにしたアクリルキーホルダー＆ステッカー、＆新曲ビジュアルのブランケットはシヒロアヤカ先生描き下ろしです！是非ゲットしてね！
Featuring the acrylic keychain & sticker with the logo of our live & new song "ROSE of the LAMP," and the new song visual blanket drawn by Shihiro Ayaka-sensei! Be sure to get them!
あれ？これは噂のアキロゼ睡眠事件？
Huh? Is this the rumored Aki Rosenthal sleeping incident?
この黒Tシャツを着て、この後はメンバーシップ限定のアルコールアンコールライブにレッツゴー！ばいばーい！
Put on this black T-shirt and let's go to the membership-only alcohol encore live right after this! Bye-bye!